<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: About | PROXI]]></title>
  <link href="http://psi-proxi.github.io/blog/categories/about/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://psi-proxi.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-02T23:14:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://psi-proxi.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ProteomeXchange Consortium]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About PROXI]]></title>
    <link href="http://psi-proxi.github.io/blog/2015/01/30/about/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-30T15:30:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://psi-proxi.github.io/blog/2015/01/30/about</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <b>Protein expression information</b> (both identification and quantification) is fundamental for understanding the function of the living organisms. An increasing amount of the mass spectrometry (MS)-based proteomics data generated is
     made available in public proteomics repositories such as <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/pride/archive/">PRIDE</a> , <a href="http://http://gpmdb.thegpm.org/">GPMDB</a> and <a href="http://www.peptideatlas.org/">PeptideAtlas</a>. 
     In addition, protein expression information can be accessed in other resources like the antibody-based <a href="http://www.proteinatlas.org/">Human Protein Atlas</a> and protein knowledge bases such as
     <a href="http://www.uniprot.org/">UniProt</a> or <a href="http://www.nextprot.org/">neXtProt</a>. At present, scientists need to access the different proteomics resources when they want to get all existing information about a given protein. The alternative is to access knowledge
     bases such as UniProt or neXtProt, but the amount of data coming from MS proteomics repositories in these resources is still limited. The main goal behind the development of PROXI is to support researchers by making possible a distributed
     search of protein expression data through heterogeneous resources like the ones outlined above, among others. The idea is to enable a biological-centric distributed search taking into account sample related metadata such as location
     (e.g. tissue, cell type) and level of expression, detection in disease states, etc. The basic idea is then to provide a common entry point for showing information coming from different data resources. Apart from these resources,
     the PROXI framework is expected to be used by other third-party applications, e.g. proteomes browsers such as <a href="http://www.proteomebrowser.org/tpb/home.jspx">&#8220;The Proteome Browser”</a> or lab-centric resources. 
</p>




<p>
   A similar service has been successfully developed for molecular interaction resources: <a href="https://code.google.com/p/psicquic/">PSICQUIC (The PSI Common Query InterfaCe)</a>. 
   Current protein expression resources give access to the data using two different approaches: (i) per individual dataset, or (ii) providing an aggregated view of the proteome:
</p>


<p><b>(i) Dataset View</b>: It is an experiment, assay or MS-run (in the case of MS-based proteomics) oriented view. This approach provides the information of one “experimental unit” meaning that no data aggregation process was applied.</p>

<p><b>(ii) Aggregated View</b>: It can be considered as the result of the aggregation of different experiments, assays or MS-runs (in the case of MS-based proteomics), using the protein as the central point for the aggregation.
For example, PeptideAtlas allows the users to retrieve the information for a specific protein identified in different experiments.</p>

<p>PROXI will be developed with the following main general tasks in mind:</p>


<p>  <b> T1. </b> Integrate protein and peptide expression information from the current MS proteomics resources such as PeptideAtlas, <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/pride/archive/">PRIDE</a>, <a href="http://http://gpmdb.thegpm.org/">GPMDB</a>,
               MassIVE and potentially others. </br>
  <b> T2. </b> Integrate protein expression information from other resources such as antibody-based resources (e.g.Human Protein Atlas) or from protein knowledge bases such as <a href="http://www.uniprot.org/">UniProt</a> or
               <a href="http://www.nextprot.org/">neXtProt</a>. </br>
  <b> T3. </b> Make possible for users to query by sample related metadata (e.g. tissue or cell type) to retrieve all the related expression information. </br>
  <b> T4. </b> Enable the export of the results in a single tabular file format or by using JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) objects. </br>
  <b> T5. </b> Define a common query language (PXQL) as a way to enable more powerful and flexible queries, by using a specific syntax. </br>
  <b> T6. </b> Implement a standard REST web service and a service registry containing a defined list of well-documented methods. </br></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
