<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Use Cases | PROXI]]></title>
  <link href="http://psi-proxi.github.io/blog/categories/use-cases/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://psi-proxi.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-03T15:30:22+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://psi-proxi.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ProteomeXchange Consortium]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PROXI Use Cases]]></title>
    <link href="http://psi-proxi.github.io/blog/2015/02/03/proxi-use-cases/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-03T14:38:09+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://psi-proxi.github.io/blog/2015/02/03/proxi-use-cases</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following use cases have driven the development of the PROXI and are used to define the scope of the system:</p>




<ul> 
 <li> PROXI should be simple and robust enough to make accessible data from disparate resources using simple tab-separated file format and JSON objects. This should facilitate the sharing of data beyond the borders
      of the proteomics field and make it more accessible to non-experts.</li>

 <li> There should be sufficient information stored in the output to facilitate data comparison, exchange and (limited) verification of protein expression information.</li>

 <li> The system will provide two different views of the data available: (i) dataset view, (ii) aggregated view. The dataset is an “experimental unit” oriented view (e.g. a MS-run for a MS-based proteomics experiment).
      The aggregated view can be considered as a condensed way to access different experiments or assays, keeping the protein as the central point of aggregation.</li>
       
 <li> It should be possible to export results of a protein expression experiment in a single file, including identification and quantification results. It should be also possible to save both the dataset and aggregated
      outputs in the same output.</li>
       
 <li> It should be flexible enough to be able to capture other expression information such as: antibody-based protein experimental information.</li>
 
 <li> It should be defined a common query language (PXQL), a way to allow more powerful and flexible queries by using a specific syntax when doing the searches.</li>

 <li> It will standardize the way of exchanging expression data from spectra information to quantitative values, including post-translational modifications, sample metadata, etc.</li>

 <li> It will define a common API to exchange Protein Expression data including a reference implementation to be use for those groups without bioinformatics supports. 
 
 <li> It should be possible to implement of standard REST web services and a service registry containing a well-defined list of methods following the PROXI API </li>
 
 <li> The existence of an open-source reference implementation for PROXI should allow the straightforward setup of a local server for protein expression data in a feasible way. The PROXI project site should offer open-source
      client libraries and code examples for software developers.</li>
</ul>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
